Hudson River Sloop Clearwater, Inc. Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 4. John Mylod’s Projects and Interests, 1981 - 1995; 4; 4 Linear Feet Boxes: 49 - 53 Folders: 1411 - 1653
  - Hudson River Fishery Management Program Study (Folder 1514, Box 50)
  - Hudson River Greenway Act Revision (Folder 1515, Box 50)
  - Hudson River Habitat Restoration Meeting (Folder 1516, Box 50)
  - Hudson River Legislation 1987, Striped Bass Info (Folder 1517, Box 50)
  - Hudson River Park Conservancy (Folder 1518, Box 50)
  - Hudson River Park Legislation (Folder 1519, Box 50)
  - Hudson River Psychiatric Center (Folder 1520, Box 50)
  - Hudson River Utilities Settlement Agreement, May 1981 - E/I Studies (Folder 1521, Box 50)
  - Hudson Stripers’ Influence on New England Sportfishery (Folder 1522, Box 50)
  - Ice House (1) (Folder 1523, Box 51)
  - Ice House (2) (Folder 1524, Box 51)
  - Ice House (3) (Folder 1525, Box 51)
  - Ice House (4) (Folder 1526, Box 51)
  - Ice House Planning Board Minutes, Verbatim Transcription (Folder 1527, Box 51)
  - Ice House Poughkeepsie, 1984 (Folder 1528, Box 51)
  - Independent Cement Tire Burning Proposal, 1994 (Folder 1529, Box 51)
  - Iona Island 1991-1992 (Folder 1530, Box 51)
  - Iona Island Center 1992-1993 (Folder 1531, Box 51)
  - Joint Water Project Draft EIS (Folder 1532, Box 51)
  - Joint Water Project Final EIS (Folder 1533, Box 51)
  - The Judicial Process and State Environmental Quality Review Act (Daniel Riesel) (Folder 1534, Box 51)
  - Lanahan Appointment to the New York State Environmental Board (Folder 1535, Box 51)
  - Land Sale Moratorium (Folder 1536, Box 51)
  - Lehigh Cement-Tire Burning (Folder 1537, Box 51)
  - List of Finfish of the HRCoop Area of Concern (Summer 1981) (Folder 1538, Box 51)
  - Long Term Hudson River PCB Analysis Project - Draft (Folder 1539, Box 51)
  - Lower Hudson River Creel Survey Report, Summer 1980 (Folder 1540, Box 51)
  - Marcy Faxes 11/8/1991 (Folder 1541, Box 51)
  - Marcy-South Project: Permit Application No. 83-825-YS (Folder 1542, Box 51)
  - Media List (Folder 1543, Box 51)
  - Millbrook Marsh Watershed Study (Folder 1544, Box 51)
  - Miller Highway Reconstruction Project (Folder 1545, Box 51)
  - Mills Mansion/Hoyt House Development Proposal (Folder 1546, Box 51)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (legal size) (Folder 1547, Box 51)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Files (Folder 1548, Box 51)
  - Mystery Point (Folder 1549, Box 51)
  - New Netherland Project (Folder 1550, Box 51)
  - New York Environmental Institute (Folder 1551, Box 51)
  - New York-New Jersey Harbor Estuary (Folder 1552, Box 51)
  - New York Rivers United (Folder 1553, Box 51)
  - New York Sportsman (Folder 1554, Box 51)
  - New York State Canal System (Folder 1555, Box 51)
  - New York State Electricity Needs (Folder 1556, Box 51)
  - New York State NRDC Unit (Folder 1557, Box 51)
  - New York State Water Saving Pumping Fixtures (Folder 1558, Box 51)
  - Newburgh Sludge Processing Facility (Folder 1559, Box 51)
  - North River STP (Folder 1560, Box 51)
  - Notes (Folder 1561, Box 51)
  - Notes on Pollution (legal size) (Folder 1562, Box 51)
  - Notice of Motion for Leave to Appear as Amici Curiae (Folder 1563, Box 51)
  - NRDC - Jamaica Bay (Folder 1564, Box 51)
  - NRDC - NOAA (Folder 1565, Box 51)
  - NYACK Sewage (Folder 1566, Box 51)
  - Office of the General Services 1990 (Folder 1567, Box 52)
  - Ossining DOT Property (Folder 1568, Box 52)
  - Paul Keller Re: Hudson River Estuary Coordinator (Folder 1569, Box 52)
  - PCBs (Folder 1570, Box 52)
  - PCBs in Hudson River Striped Bass, 1984 (Folder 1571, Box 52)
  - PCB Reclamation Project (Folder 1572, Box 52)
  - Pesticides - DEET 1995 (Folder 1573, Box 52)
  - Platforms and Piers - Habitat Value (Folder 1574, Box 52)
  - Port of Albany Cogeneration Facility (Folder 1575, Box 52)
  - Poughkeepsie Sand Dock Rd. Recycling Facility (Folder 1576, Box 52)
  - Preliminary Shad Marketing Proposal, Jan. 1985 (Folder 1577, Box 52)
  - Preserve Hudson and Erie Canal Corridors (Folder 1578, Box 52)
  - Proceedings and Papers of the National Fishery Congress (Folder 1579, Box 52)
  - A Progress Report: Ellis Island Bridge and Access Alternatives (Folder 1580, Box 52)
  - Proposal for Research Foundation (Folder 1581, Box 52)
  - Proposed Draft Environmental Impact Statement for Striped Bass in the Hudson River 2/28/1984 (Folder 1582, Box 52)
  - Proposed Hudson River Monitoring Program (Folder 1583, Box 52)
  - Proposed Revisions to 6NYCRR Parts 200, 201, 231 (Folder 1584, Box 52)
  - To Protect the Hudson: Clearwater’s Environmental Action Program (Folder 1585, Box 52)
  - Public Service Commission: James Bay (Folder 1586, Box 52)
  - Public Transit Doctrine (Folder 1587, Box 52)
  - Quassaick Creek (Folder 1588, Box 52)
  - Radioactive Waste (Folder 1589, Box 52)
  - Real Estate Transfer Tax Info (Folder 1590, Box 52)
  - Record on Appeal Re: Board of Education Pine Plains Central School District (Folder 1591, Box 52)
  - Redevelopment of Deteriorated Urban Waterfronts (Folder 1592, Box 52)
  - Rensselaer Power 1991-1992 (Folder 1593, Box 52)
  - Resolution 10/13/1983 (Folder 1594, Box 52)
  - Revised Views of Clearwater “Action” Program (legal size) (Folder 1595, Box 52)
  - Right to Know More Act - New York State 1993 Legislation (Folder 1596, Box 52)
  - Right to Know More Legislation - Federal (Folder 1597, Box 52)
  - Right to Know More Working Notes Newsletter (Folder 1598, Box 52)
  - Rockefeller Institute of Government 25th Anniversary Study of the DEC (Folder 1599, Box 52)
  - Rockland Recycling Facility (Folder 1600, Box 52)
  - RSR Nationwide (Folder 1601, Box 52)
  - SAG Court of Appeals, Aug. 1989 (Folder 1602, Box 52)
  - Scientific American (Folder 1603, Box 52)
  - Scientists/Experts (Folder 1604, Box 52)
  - Seabrook 1978 (Folder 1605, Box 52)
  - Seaport (Folder 1606, Box 52)
  - Sediment Campaign - Sample (Folder 1607, Box 52)
  - Settlement Agreement Re: Hudson River Power Plants (Folder 1608, Box 52)
  - Shad Controversy (Folder 1609, Box 52)
  - Shad Miscellaneous (Folder 1610, Box 52)
  - Sing-Sing Regional Medical Unit, Ossining (Folder 1611, Box 52)
  - Snow Dock, 1991 (Folder 1612, Box 52)
  - Social Services Relocation (Folder 1613, Box 52)
  - Solid Waste Policy 1988 (Folder 1614, Box 52)
  - Source Report, April 1988 (Folder 1615, Box 52)
  - State Land Biodiversity Conservation Act (Folder 1616, Box 52)
  - State Pollutant Discharge Elimination System - Discharge Permit (Folder 1617, Box 52)
  - Statement of Ian Goodman Re: Hydro-Quebec Power (Folder 1618, Box 52)
  - Stone, Ward W.P.U. (Folder 1619, Box 52)
  - Stream Best Uses (no title) (Folder 1620, Box 52)
  - Stream Reclassification (Folder 1621, Box 52)
  - Striped Bass (Folder 1622, Box 52)
  - Striped Bass Bill, 1993 (Folder 1623, Box 52)
  - Striped Bass Management Bill (Folder 1624, Box 52)
  - Striped Bass Miscellaneous, 1986 (Folder 1625, Box 52)
  - Striped Bass Regulations, 5/8/87 (Folder 1626, Box 52)
  - St. Simon 1989-1990 (Folder 1627, Box 52)
  - Studholme/Able Platform Proposal (Folder 1628, Box 52)
  - Surface Action Group (Folder 1629, Box 52)
  - Tom Lake, Fishing (Folder 1630, Box 52)
  - Town of Poughkeepsie Recycling Facility (Folder 1631, Box 52)
  - Toxins in River Fish (Folder 1632, Box 52)
  - Transit 1992 (Folder 1633, Box 53)
  - Ulster County 1994 Mega Dump (Folder 1634, Box 53)
  - Update on Marine Environmental Consequences of Tidal Power Development (Folder 1635, Box 53)
  - Upper Hudson Catch and Release Fishery (Folder 1636, Box 53)
  - Up River Projects 1992 (Folder 1637, Box 53)
  - USGS - Hudson River Flow Green Island Gauging Stat. (Folder 1638, Box 53)
  - Utilities’ Biological Monitoring Program (Folder 1639, Box 53)
  - Utilities Hudson River Monitoring Program (Folder 1640, Box 53)
  - Utility Low Income Energy Efficiency Program (Folder 1641, Box 53)
  - Village of Odayak (Folder 1642, Box 53)
  - Ward Stone/Reynolds Metals, 1988 (Folder 1643, Box 53)
  - Water Conservation Programs and Related Activities of the New York City DEP (Folder 1644, Box 53)
  - Waterfront Community 1987 (Folder 1645, Box 53)
  - Water Quality Programs DEC Reg. 3 (Folder 1646, Box 53)
  - Water Quality Standards Lawsuit (Folder 1647, Box 53)
  - Water Resources Management Strategy (Folder 1648, Box 53)
  - Westway Highway Project (Folder 1649, Box 53)
  - Williamsburg Bridge Sandblasting (Folder 1650, Box 53)
  - Workshop on Critical Data Needs for Shad Research on Atlantic Coast of North America, Feb. 8-9, 1984 (Folder 1651, Box 53)
  - Writings by Thomas Berry (Folder 1652, Box 53)
  - Zebra Mussels (Folder 1653, Box 53)
- 5. Clippings, 1987 - 1994; 5; 1 Linear Foot Box: 53 Folders: 1654 - 1680
  Newspaper clippings covering Clearwater events, actions, and environmental concerns
  Alphabetical by subject
  - Boat Clips Pre 1992 (Folder 1654, Box 53)
  - Boat Clips 1992-1993 (Folder 1655, Box 53)
  - Earth Day 1993 (Folder 1656, Box 53)
  - Education Pre 1992 (Folder 1657, Box 53)
  - General Clips 1994 (Folder 1658, Box 53)
  - General Clearwater Clips, Pre 1992 (Folder 1659, Box 53)
  - General Clearwater Clips, 1992-1993 (Folder 1660, Box 53)
  - General Environmental (Folder 1661, Box 53)
  - Historical (Folder 1662, Box 53)
  - Land Use/Waterfront Pre 1992 (Folder 1663, Box 53)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 1664, Box 53)
  - New York Commercial Fisherman’s Association (Folder 1665, Box 53)
  - PCB Clippings (Folder 1666, Box 53)
  - PCB/H2O Pollution Pre 1992 (Folder 1667, Box 53)
  - PCB Soloman Pres (Folder 1668, Box 53)
  - PCBs/Water Pollution 1992-1993 (Folder 1669, Box 53)
  - Revival 1994 5.25 disks (Folder 1670, Box 53)
  - Sewage Petition (Folder 1671, Box 53)
  - Sloop Clearwater (1983) (Folder 1672, Box 53)
  - Sloop Clearwater (1984) (Folder 1673, Box 53)
  - Sloop Clearwater (1985) (Folder 1674, Box 53)
  - Sloop Clearwater (1988) (Folder 1675, Box 53)
  - Solid Waste, General Environmental Clippings (Folder 1676, Box 53)
  - WBPM (Folder 1677, Box 53)
  - Westway Clippings (Folder 1678, Box 53)
  - Wildlife/Fish 1992-1993 (Folder 1679, Box 53)
  - Winter Maintenance Report 1987-1988 (Folder 1680, Box 53)
- 6. Photographs, 6; 1 Linear Foot Box: 54 Folders: 1681 - 1715
  Photographs documenting Clearwater events and the Sloop
  - 1991 4-ups (Folder 1681, Box 54)
  - Access (Folder 1682, Box 54)
  - Access at Revival (Folder 1683, Box 54)
  - Activists (Folder 1684, Box 54)
  - Album (no folder - should be taken apart) (Folder 1685, Box 54)
  - Arm of the Sea (Folder 1686, Box 54)
  - Children Revival (Folder 1687, Box 54)
  - Children/Stage, etc. (Folder 1688, Box 54)
  - Children’s Area, Credit: Paule Epstein (Folder 1689, Box 54)
  - Clearwater Tent (Folder 1690, Box 54)
  - Contacts 1987 (Folder 1691, Box 54)
  - Crafts (Folder 1692, Box 54)
  - Dancing (Folder 1693, Box 54)
  - Disabled (Folder 1694, Box 54)
  - For Displays (Folder 1695, Box 54)
  - General Audience (Folder 1696, Box 54)
  - Juggling (Folder 1697, Box 54)
  - New Boat (Folder 1698, Box 54)
  - Pete and Toshi (Folder 1699, Box 54)
  - Press Release (Folder 1700, Box 54)
  - Printed Enlarged Photographs (Folder 1701, Box 54)
  - Pumpkin Sail 1991 (Folder 1702, Box 54)
  - Recycling at Revival (Folder 1703, Box 54)
  - Revival 1991 (and Proofs) Photos by Jerry Skrocki (Folder 1704, Box 54)
  - Revival 1992 (and Contacts) (Folder 1705, Box 54)
  - Revival 1992 Performers (Folder 1706, Box 54)
  - Revival 1994 Performers (Folder 1707, Box 54)
  - Revival 1994 Proofs, Credit: Bob Yahn (Folder 1708, Box 54)
  - Revival Miscellaneous (Folder 1709, Box 54)
  - Sign Language Interpretation (Folder 1710, Box 54)
  - Slides and Captions (Folder 1711, Box 54)
  - Slides Revival 1984 (Folder 1712, Box 54)
  - Sloop P.R. Photos - To Send Out (Folder 1713, Box 54)
  - Small Boats (Folder 1714, Box 54)
  - Volunteers (Folder 1715, Box 54)
- 7. Clearwater Founding Materials, 7; 1.5 Linear Feet Boxes: 55 - 56 Folders: 1716 - 1747
  Papers documenting the beginning and progression of the Sloop Clearwater organization
  - Subseries 7.1: New Boat Files, 1987 - 1998; 7.1; Box: 55 Folders: 1716 - 1732
    Materials pertaining to the need for a second sloop
    - Appraisal 1991-1992 (Folder 1716, Box 55)
    - Case for a New Hudson River Sloop (Folder 1717, Box 55)
    - The Construction of a Second Sloop Feasibility Analysis (Folder 1718, Box 55)
    - Correspondence (Folder 1719, Box 55)
    - DeLaval Property (Folder 1720, Box 55)
    - Draft New Boat Committee Report (Folder 1721, Box 55)
    - Hazardous Waste (Folder 1722, Box 55)
    - Maps (Folder 1723, Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 1724, Box 55)
    - New Boat 1987-1988 (Folder 1725, Box 55)
    - New Boat 1989 (Folder 1726, Box 55)
    - New Boat 1990-1991 (Folder 1727, Box 55)
    - New Boat 1992 (Folder 1728, Box 55)
    - New Boat 1997-1998 (Folder 1729, Box 55)
    - New Boat Committee Proposal 1 (Folder 1730, Box 55)
    - New Boat Committee Proposal 2 (Folder 1731, Box 55)
    - Proposal to Hudson River Sloop Clearwater from Piermont Associates (Folder 1732, Box 55)
  - Subseries 7.2: Founding Materials, 7.2; Box: 55 Folders: 1733 - 1745
    Materials pertaining to the history and founding of the Hudson River Sloop Clearwater
    - 1960’s (Folder 1733, Box 55)
    - 1970’s (Folder 1734, Box 55)
    - 1980’s (Folder 1735, Box 55)
    - 1990’s (Folder 1736, Box 55)
    - Clearwater Second Annual Report and State of the Hudson (Folder 1737, Box 55)
    - The First Clearwater Worksheets (Folder 1738, Box 55)
    - History of Sloop (Folder 1739, Box 55)
    - The Hudson River: A Resource Restored (Folder 1740, Box 55)
    - Hudson Slooper’s Handy Guide (Folder 1741, Box 55)
    - Hudson Valley Profile (Folder 1742, Box 55)
    - Pete Seeger (Folder 1743, Box 55)
    - River Pollution/Clean-up Articles (Folder 1744, Box 55)
    - Strategic Planning Committee (Folder 1745, Box 55)
  - Subseries 7.3: Oversized Materials, 7.3; Box: 56 Folders: 1746 - 1747
    Oversized materials pertaining to the development of Clearwater
    - Parade (Folder 1746, Box 56)
    - The Troubled Hudson Filmstrip and Cassette Series (Folder 1747, Box 56)